<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oldies on </title>
    <link>/tags/oldies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oldies on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 15:04:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/oldies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be a Networker?</title>
      <link>/post/technical/2008-10-20-how-to-be-a-networker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 15:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/technical/2008-10-20-how-to-be-a-networker/</guid>
      <description>Well, Lets say that most of the People have wrong concept of Who is A network Engineer and whose not,in Order to Clarify this Vague concept among people and also to answer the question that almost Most students or young Engineers ask them selves “How to be a Networker ?”, I will First Define who is A newtork Engineer.
A Network Engineer is A Guy who takes the best of both worlds (Communications and Computer Science) and merge them into one to get into the “Communter Science ” world 😀 ,so A Network Engineer is like a federal spy, he can get into a room full of aliens and never be exposed, also most people think that some Certifications will make you a network Engineer that easily, well I admit that certifications give you quite a good understanding of IT stuff but not Engineering stuff, anyway lets get to the second Question already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing &amp; LTE</title>
      <link>/post/technical/2009-01-20-cloud-lte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/technical/2009-01-20-cloud-lte/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking for a while, what would it be like in 3 or 4 years ahead, and I started noticing that everybody is starting to love the “Cloud”, I won’t lie, I love it to :D, It is exponentially increasing, some of the ISP’s have already started using the cloud, it is a pretty neat concept, for some of you who are not familiar with the cloud: Imagine that you are subscribing to a bank and you are no longer keeping your money under you bed :D, well everybody doesn’t now, no body is hiding his money under his bed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>